

CONTACT

- +84 90 466 1405
- Hanoi, Vietnam

SKILLS

BACK-END

- Laravel
- Symfony
- MySQL
- RESTful API
- Node.js

FRONT-END

- Livewire
- Vue.is
- Alpine.js
- Tailwind
- Bootstrap

DEV-OPS

- Docker
- GIT
- AWS
- Bash Scripting
- Composer

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

Multimedia, Programming and Design Technological University of the Shannon - Moylish Campus

FETAC 5

Multimedia
Limerick College of Further Education

TADG KEATING-WEBB

PHP DEVELOPER

PROFILE

PHP Developer with 10 years experience specialising in the Laravel and Symfony frameworks.

My passion is writing clean test driven PHP but I am also very comfortable working with front-end technologies.

Originally from Ireland and now based in Hanoi, Vietnam, I am currently looking for either remote or on-site Software developer or Technical lead positions within a company using PHP as there back-end technology of choice .

WORK EXPERIENCE

PHP Developer

2024 - PRESENT

Freelance

- Implemented applications in both Symfony and Laravel.
- Worked with Livewire 3 alongside Alpine JS for reactive Laravel sites.
- Vue.js for a reactive Symfony frontend.
- Greatly improved frontend development skill set with a strong focus on mastering Tailwind.
- Worked as both a part of an agile team, attending weekly meetings with members across time zones and also as a solo developer on smaller projects.

Senior Software Developer

2021 - 2023

Sutunam LTD

- Worked on a variety of sites from large e-commerce to smaller sports based websites.
- Mastered Symfony Framework and leveraging Doctrine to build efficient database queries.
- Focused on improving an in-house ETL tool, bringing it up to the latest version of Symfony and implementing service passes.
- Primarily focused on consuming data from various REST and SOAP APIs and transforming into a format to to be consumed a Magento 2 API and vice versa: transforming order and stock data from Magento back to ERPs or CRMs.
- Refactored common features used across in-house Symfony sites to be composer packages to allow re-usability across multiple sites.
- Spearheaded a campaign to get all developers in the company to work with docker and built specific docker images for older projects.
- Followed strict git flow principles to ensure smooth operations when working on a a project with a larger team.
- Supported and mentored junior developers in best practices, such as SOLID and KISS.

LANGUAGES

- English (Native)
- Vietnamese (Intermediate)

Lead Developer (Freelance Contract)

2020 - 2021

Greenfi LTD

- Took over solo development of an environmental management website.
- Successfully handled updating to the latest version of Laravel and deploying to AWS.
- · Worked closely with the client to quickly fix any bugs after deployment or implement any features that arose during field testing.

Developer (Freelance Contract)

2019 - 2020

Greenfi LTD

- Worked as backend developer as a part of an international team to construct an environmental monitoring website and API powered by the Laravel framework.
- Took part in an agile work environment attending weekly meetings with the team from initial specification phase through to version 1.0 being completed.
- Constructed a RESTful API to be consumed by an associated mobile application.
- · Worked closely alongside a front-end developer to implement their design work.

PHP Developer

2015 - 2019

Freelance

- Worked on a variety of websites for international clients.
- Largely focused on the e-commerce field.
- Worked as both a member of a remote team or at times as a solo developer on a project.
- Worked with multiple PHP frameworks: initially focusing on CakePHP, before mastering Laravel.,

Part-time Lecturer

2014 - 2015

Technological University of the Shannon - Moylish Campus

- Tutored students who had learning difficulties or were otherwise struggling in PHP development.
- · Successfully balanced my final year of study with my teaching responsibilities.

PHP Developer Internship

2014 - 2014

CakeCoded

- 6 month internship working with a mentor to learn how to run a freelance web development company.
- Gained hands-on experience in client interactions, including gathering requirements and transitioning them to technical solutions as well as learning to deal with and manage client expectations.

REFERENCE

Tanguy Rambaud

Mark Ellis-Jones Greenfi LTD / CEO

Sutunam LTD / CEO

Email: mark@greenfi.io

Phone: (+84) 024 3573 9741

Email: rtanguy@sutunam.com